How does anesthesia /ˌænɪsˈθiːzɪə 麻醉/ work
If you've had surgery /ˈsɜːdʒərɪ/,
you might remember starting to count
backwards from ten,
nine,
eight,
and then waking up with the surgery
already over before you even got to five.
And it might seem like you were asleep,
but you weren't.
You were under anesthesia /ˌænɪsˈθiːzɪə 麻醉/,
which is much more complicated.
You were unconscious /ʌnˈkɒnʃəs 无意识/,
but you also couldn't move,
form memories,
or, hopefully, feel pain.
Without being able to block all those
processes at once,
many surgeries would be
way too traumatic /trɔːˈmætɪk 痛苦的；创伤的/ to perform.
Ancient medical texts from Egypt,
Asia and the Middle East
all describe early anesthetics /ˌænɪsˈθɛtɪk 麻醉剂/
containing things like opium /ˈəʊpɪəm 鸦片/ poppy /pɔpi 罂粟/,
mandrake /ˈmændreɪk 欧茄参/ fruit,
and alcohol.
Today, anesthesiologists /ˌænɪsˌθiːzɪˈɒlədʒɪst/ often combine
regional, inhalational /ˌɪnhəˈleɪʃənəl 吸入的/
and intravenous /ˌɪntrəˈviːnəs 静脉注射/ agents
to get the right balance for a surgery.
Regional /区域的/ anesthesia /ˌænɪsˈθiːzɪə/ blocks pain signals
from a specific part of the body
from getting to the brain.
Pain and other messages travel through
the nervous system as electrical impulses.
Regional anesthetics work by setting up
an electrical barricade /ˈbærɪˌkeɪd 路障 障碍物/.
They bind to the proteins
in neurons' /ˈnjʊərəʊn 神经元/ cell membranes /ˈmɛmbreɪn 膜/
that let charged particles /ˈpɑːtɪkəl 微粒/ in and out,
and lock out positively /ˈpɒzɪtɪvlɪ 明确地/ charged particles.
One compound that does this is cocaine /koʊˈkeɪn  可卡因/,
whose painkilling effects
were discovered by accident
when an ophthalmology /ˌɒfθælˈmɒlədʒɪ 眼科学/ intern /ˈɪnˌtɜrn 实习生/
got some on his tongue /tʌŋ/.
It's still occasionally used
as an anesthetic,
but many of the more common
regional anesthetics
have a similar chemical structure
and work the same way.
But for major surgeries where you need
to be unconscious,
you'll want something that acts
on the entire nervous system,
including the brain.
That's what inhalational /ˌɪnhəˈleɪʃənəl 吸入的/ anesthetics do.
In Western medicine, diethyl /daiˈeθil 二乙基/ ether /ˈiːθə 醚/
was the first common one.
It was best known as a recreational drug
until doctors started to realize that
people sometimes didn't notice
injuries they received
under the influence /ˈɪnflʊəns 影响/.
In the 1840s, they started sedating /sɪˈdeɪt 给…服镇静剂/
patients with ether /ˈiːθə 醚/
during dental extractions /ɪkˈstrækʃən 抽出/ and surgeries.
Nitrous /ˈnaɪtrəs 氮的/ oxide /ˈɒksaɪd 氧化物/ became popular
in the decades that followed
and is still used today.
although ether /ˈiːθə 醚/ derivatives /dɪˈrɪvətɪv 衍生物/,
like sevoflurane /sevəˈfluərein 七氟烷/, are more common.
Inhalational /ˌɪnhəˈleɪʃənəl 吸入的/ anesthesia is usually
supplemented /sʌplimənt 补遗/ with intravenous /ˌɪntrəˈviːnəs 静脉注射/ anesthesia,
which was developed in the 1870s.
Common intravenous /ˌɪntrəˈviːnəs 静脉注射/ agents include
sedatives /ˈsɛdətɪv 镇静剂/, like propofol /丙酚/,
which induce unconsciousness,
and opioids /ˈəʊpɪˌɔɪd 类鸦片药物/, like fentanyl /ˈfentəˌnaɪl 芬太尼/,
which reduce pain.
These general anesthetics
also seem to work
by affecting electrical signals
in the nervous system.
Normally, the brain's electrical signals
are a chaotic chorus /ˈkɔːrəs 合唱/
as different parts of the brain
communicate with each other.
That connectivity keeps you awake
and aware.
But as someone becomes anesthetized,
those signals become calmer /kɑːm 镇定/
and more organized,
suggesting that different
parts of the brain
aren't talking to each other anymore.
There's a lot we still don't know
about exactly how this happens.
Several common anesthetics bind to
the GABA-A receptor in the brain's neurons /ˈnjʊərəʊn/.
They hold the gateway open,
letting negatively charged particles /ˈpɑːtɪkəl 微粒/
flow into the cell.
Negative charge builds up
and acts like a log  jam /dʒæm 堵塞/ 木头塞子,
keeping the neuron from transmitting
electrical signals.
The nervous system has lots
of these gated channels,
controlling pathways for movement,
memory,
and consciousness.
Most anesthetics probably
act on more than one,
and they don't act on
just the nervous system.
Many anesthetics also affect the heart,
lungs,
and other vital organs.
Just like early anesthetics,
which included familiar poisons like
hemlock /ˈhemˌlɒk 铁杉/ and aconite /ækənait 乌头/,
modern drugs can
have serious /ˈsɪərɪəs 严重的/ side effects.
So an anesthesiologist has to mix
just the right balance of drugs
to create all the features of anesthesia,
while carefully monitoring
the patient's vital signs,
and adjusting the drug mixture as needed.
Anesthesia is complicated,
but figuring out how to use it
allowed for the development
of new and better surgical techniques.
Surgeons could learn how to routinely /ruːˈtiːnlɪ 常规地/
and safely perform C-sections,
reopen blocked arteries /ˈɑːtərɪ 动脉/,
replace damaged livers and kidneys /ˈkɪdnɪ 肾脏/,
and many other life-saving operations.
And each year, new anesthesia techniques
are developed
that will ensure more and more patients
survive the trauma /ˈtrɔːmə 痛苦/ of surgery.